1969年7月20日，阿波罗11号在月球着陆
On the 20th of July, 1969, Apollo 11 landed on the Moon.
全世界大约有6亿人观看了尼尔·阿姆斯特朗在月球踩下第一个脚印的直播
600 million people around the world watched as Neil Armstrong took mankind's first steps onto the Lunar surface.
那一刻记录了一代人兴奋的回忆
This moment captured the excitement of a generation
也让肯尼迪总统在60年代末登月的承诺得以兑现
and fulfilled President Kennedy's goal of landing a man on the Moon by the end of the decade.
可NASA是如何让月球上的画面一路传回地球让无数人看到的？
But how did NASA broadcast live footage from the Moon all the way to a record amount of people back on Earth?
本期视频，我们将了解视频直播画面从月球传回时会遇到的挑战
In this video, we're going to look at the the challenges involved in broadcasting live footage from the Moon.
并了解克服这些挑战所用到的技术
We're also going to look at the technology that went into making it happen
以及这些技术在之后的阿波罗任务中有何改进
and how it was developed for future Apollo missions.
在60年代早期，NASA开始着手研发送人类登月的火箭和飞船
In the early 60's, NASA began working on the rocket and spacecraft that would eventually take humans to the Moon.
可当时美国送进太空的宇航员屈指可数
At the time, America had only sent a handful of astronauts into space,
更没有人离开过近地轨道
and no human had ever left Earth's orbit.
送人类登月这个充满野心的计划遭到了无数质疑
This ambitious plan to send humans to the Moon was met with a lot of skepticism
所以NASA也明白宇航员在月球行走的直播将是登月任务最有力的证明
and NASA knew that live video of the astronauts walking on the Moon would be crucial for the mission's credibility.
NASA与美国西屋公司签约，要求后者设计制造一款小型黑白相机
NASA contracted electronics company "Westinghouse" to design and manufacture a small black and white camera
从而拍摄人类首次登月的镜头
that would be capable of capturing man's first step on the Moon.
相机需能在仅7瓦的功耗下运转
This camera would need to operate on a mere 7 Watt power source
并能承受月球表面的强烈辐射与巨大温差
and be able to survive the harsh radiation and extreme temperatures found on the Moon's surface.
最重要的是，登月舱还需要将视频直播画面
Most importantly, the Lunar Module would need to be able to send the live video feed
和其他无线电、遥测数据一起传回地球
all the way back to Earth, along with the other radio and telemetry data that was already being sent back.
NASA意识到阿波罗任务需要一款全新的通信系统
NASA realized that the Apollo missions would require a brand new communications system
才能把数据从月球传回地球
in order to send data back from the Moon.
于是他们研发了一款叫“统一S波段”的系统
They developed a system called "Unified S-band"
可以将各自不同频率的遥测信号、指令、声音、视频信号
which could send: telemetry, command, voice and television data using different frequencies
结合为单一天线发送
but combined into a single antenna.
美国使用的NTSC制使用525行扫描线
然而即使有了新系统，信号带宽也不够传输525行的标清电视信号
However, even with this new system, there wasn't enough bandwidth available for a standard 525 line video camera.
为了让视频流能“挤进”带宽中
In order for the video feed to fit into the downlink,
西屋公司研发了低扫描频率相机
Westinghouse developed a slow-scan camera
只传输325行扫描线、每秒仅10帧的画面
which transmitted just 325 scan lines at a mere 10 frames per second.
相机会通过线缆连接至登月舱
This camera would be connected to the Lunar Module via an electrical cable,
从而可以在着陆点附近移动
allowing it to be moved around the landing site.
视频信号会经由登月舱天线
The video signal would be transmitted from the Lunar Module's antenna
传回澳大利亚的追踪站
back to a tracking station in Australia
在澳大利亚，NASA将画面转换成标准广播电视信号
where NASA would convert the image into a standard broadcast signal.
再将信号利用通信卫星转发给休斯敦的控制中心
That signal would then be transmitted up to a communications satellite
and back down to mission control in Houston
休斯敦再将信号转发给世界其他地方
where they would broadcast it to the rest of the world.
然而，在月球开直播的挑战还没完
However, the challenges of filming on the Moon didn't stop there.
月球表面和黑暗的太空背景产生的超高对比度
The incredibly high contrast between the Lunar surface and the darkness of space
会导致在月球上捕获清晰图像异常困难
would make capturing a clear image on the Moon extremely difficult.
为解决这个问题，西屋公司使用了其曾为国防部研发的绝密技术
To solve this problem, Westinghouse used a piece of classified technology
which they had developed for the Department of Defense.
他们研发了一款特制的低亮度成像管
They had developed a special low-light imaging tube
其曾在越南战争中用于丛林侦查相机上
which was used on jungle surveillance cameras during the Vietnam War.
它能在低亮度下捕获移动物体，且不会让画面完全模糊
This could capture moving objects at low light levels without completely blurring the image.
随着人类首次登月任务的逐渐接近，相机也准备好了
As the first manned Apollo missions loomed ever closer, the camera was ready
它将在阿波罗9号上进行其首次、也是唯一的一次测试
and it was on Apollo 9 where it would go through it's first and only test.
相机放在了登月舱上
The camera was placed on the Lunar Module
在任务中相机和其他通信系统的测试非常成功
and the mission successfully tested the camera along with the communication system.
相机的下一个任务就是将人类第一次登月的画面直播出去
The camera's next task would be capturing man's first step onto the Moon.
1969年7月20日，阿波罗11号在月球着陆
20th of July 1969, Apollo 11 touched down on the Moon.
置于登月舱侧面的相机对准了登月舱的梯子
With the camera placed on the side of the Lunar Module aiming towards the ladders,
巴兹·奥尔德林拨动舱内的断路器，开启了相机
Buzz Aldrin hit a circuit breaker from inside the cabin to turn on the camera.
直播一开始，画面是上下颠倒的
At the start of the broadcast, the footage appeared to be upside down.
澳大利亚负责信号的技术人员很快将画面翻转回来
Video operators in Australia who were handling the signal quickly inverted the image to fix this issue,
刚好赶上阿姆斯特朗踏上月球的画面
just in time for Neil stepping onto the Moon.
尽管画面的对比度很高
There was a great deal of contrast in the image
在转换过程中丢失了很多细节
and a lot of detail was lost through the conversion process,
但镜头还是清晰地记录下这最具有历史意义的一刻
but the footage clearly captured one of the most historic moments in history.
相机在任务中运行一切顺利，且至今还在月球上
The camera performed its job perfectly throughout the mission and remains on the Moon to this day.
在之后的阿波罗任务中，NASA使用了更先进的相机
Future Apollo missions used a more advanced version of the camera
可以记录色度信息，且在低亮度下有更好的表现
which filmed in color and had better low light performance.
阿波罗15、16、17号的相机还安装在了月球车上
Apollo 15, 16 and 17 cameras were also placed onto the Lunar rover.
当宇航员离开月球的时候，他们把月球车停在一定距离外
Once the Astronauts were leaving the Moon, they parked the rover at a distance
而任务控制中心的相机操作员会发送指令让相机抬头
and a camera operator back at mission control would command the camera to tilt up,
在宇航员从月球起飞时继续跟踪拍摄
following the astronauts as they left the Moon's surface.
所以虽然我们还没重返月球
So although we have never been back to the Moon,
我们还是要感激那些为了拍下这些历史瞬间的人所付出的努力
we can appreciate the effort that went into capturing these historical moments
而那些画面将是人类永远的财富
in a way that we will cherish forever.
而当我们未来重返月球时，我们今天拥有的先进摄像技术
And when we do eventually return to the Moon, the advanced camera technology that we have today
还将拍摄更加壮丽的瞬间
will allow us to capture the moment with even more beauty.
感谢Primal Space的帮助每个视频撰写文稿查找资料的赞助者
Thank you to the Primal Space patrons who helped to write and research each video.
如果你想赞助Primal Space频道并加入我们专有Discord群
If you'd like to contribute Primal Space and join our exclusive Discord.
请访问patreon.com/primalspace
please visit patreon.com/primalspace
满100名赞助者后会再抽一位赠送土星五号乐高玩具
where we will be giving away another Saturn V Lego Set once we reach 100 patrons.
所以记得关注，方便我们讨论、学习所有和太空有关的知识
So make sure you've subscribed, so you can join the discussion as we continue to learn more about all things space.
非常感谢您的观看，我们下期视频见
Thank you very much for watching, and I'll see you in the next video.